<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nodejs on Sanyam's Homepage</title><link>https://i-sanyam.github.io/tags/nodejs/</link><description>Recent content in nodejs on Sanyam's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://i-sanyam.github.io/tags/nodejs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to automatically maintain a MySQL Table’s Partitions?</title><link>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/mysql-partition-keeper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/mysql-partition-keeper/</guid><description>We are going to talk here about time series data and Partitions in MySQL. If you are not familiar with these I highly recommend you read the prevoius blog post
Since there cannot be a infinite number of partitions, periodic maintenance of partitions - dropping old partitions and creating new ones - is required. Manual Partition Maintenance is prone to delays and errors. Read on to know how I created a script for automatic maintenance for partitions.</description></item><item><title>How to upgrade to npm packages with breaking changes?</title><link>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/upgrade-npm-backages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/upgrade-npm-backages/</guid><description>This was my first blog about tech.
I had to upgrade the mongodb npm package in our code base from version 2.2 to 3.6. Between these releases ES6 had released and async, await were introduced. Newer packages of the versions were released with the cleaner async methods instead of using callback functions. The 2.2 version used callbacks and the 3.6 version had an async API. To make matters worse, the package was used haywire everywhere in the code base which required that I change every file where this package was required.</description></item></channel></rss>