<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>best practices on Sanyam's Homepage</title><link>https://i-sanyam.github.io/tags/best-practices/</link><description>Recent content in best practices on Sanyam's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://i-sanyam.github.io/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partitioning — Reduce query time by 2000x in a MySQL table with 500M+ rows</title><link>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/mysql-reduce-query-time-2000x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/mysql-reduce-query-time-2000x/</guid><description>A lot of data in applications is time-stamped and is it is sequenced in that manner. Only the data of a defined time range will be really required in the active working of the application and the rest will just be historical data available for downloads, reports etc. A great example of this can be order history of a user. Only the past 1 month order data may be relevant and available for the user to perform some actions.</description></item><item><title>How to upgrade to npm packages with breaking changes?</title><link>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/upgrade-npm-backages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://i-sanyam.github.io/blog/upgrade-npm-backages/</guid><description>This was my first blog about tech.
I had to upgrade the mongodb npm package in our code base from version 2.2 to 3.6. Between these releases ES6 had released and async, await were introduced. Newer packages of the versions were released with the cleaner async methods instead of using callback functions. The 2.2 version used callbacks and the 3.6 version had an async API. To make matters worse, the package was used haywire everywhere in the code base which required that I change every file where this package was required.</description></item></channel></rss>